我离开了我的爱，我的爱我离开了
I left my love, my love I left
睡在她的床上
A-sleeping in her bed
我背弃了我的真爱
I turned my back on my true love
去和强尼·瑞布打了
Went fighting Johnny Reb
我给我的爱人留了一封信
I left my love a letter
在树的叫声里
In the holler of a tree
我告诉她她会找到我的
I told her she would find me
美国骑兵
In the US Cavalry
嗨，他们下去了
Hi-ho, down they go
没有"不能"这个词
There's no such word as "can't"
我们会干净利落地去地狱然后回来
We'll ride clean down to hell and back
献给尤利西斯·辛普森·格兰特
For Ulysses Simpson Grant
嗨，他们下去了
Hi-ho, down they go
没有"不能"这个词
There's no such word as "can't"
我们会干净利落地去地狱然后回来
We'll ride clean down to hell and back
献给尤利西斯·辛普森·格兰特
For Ulysses Simpson Grant
§我离开了我的爱，我的爱我离开了
§ I left my love, my love I left
§睡在她的床上
§ A-sleeping in her bed
我背弃了我的真爱
I turned my back on my true love
去和强尼·瑞布打了
Went fighting Johnny Reb
我给我的爱人留了一封信
I left my love a letter
在树的叫声里
In the holler of a tree
我告诉她她会找到我的
I told her she would find me
美国骑兵
In the US Cavalry
嗨，他们下去了
Hi-ho, down they go
没有"不能"这个词
There's no such word as "can't"
我们直接去新奥尔良
We'll ride clean down to New Orleans
献给尤利西斯·辛普森·格兰特
For Ulysses Simpson Grant
赫尔伯特将军，是约好的。
General Hurlburt, by appointment.
-赫尔伯特将军和马洛上校。-史蒂夫，进来。
- General Hurlburt and Colonel Marlowe. - Steve, come in.
你好,萨姆。马洛上校。
Hello, Sam. Colonel Marlowe.
(互相问候)
(exchange of greetings)
-谢尔曼将军，马洛上校。-你好!
- General Sherman, Colonel Marlowe. - How do you do?
马洛，我一直很想见你。
Marlowe, I've been anxious to meet you.
-很荣幸，长官  -请坐
- It's a privilege, sir. - Sit down.
-这是你第一次来维克斯堡吗? -是的，长官。
- Is this your first look at Vicksburg? - Yes, sir.
我们已经看了十个月了，我们不喜欢它。
We've been looking at it for ten months, and we don't like it.
上校，为了你好，我们这边的战争进展得一点都不顺利。
Colonel, for your benefit, the war on our side hasn't been going well at all.
在华盛顿没有，在报纸上没有，在战场上没有。
Not in Washington, not in the newspapers, not in the field.
说得委婉点，由于人手和资源的减少，
To put it mildly, with less men and less resources,
南方已经让我们停滞不前了
the South has whipped us to a standstill.
(炮火)
(cannon fire)
如果我能把维克斯堡…
Now, if I could take Vicksburg...
整个情况改变，但我必须在今年夏天做这件事。
the whole picture would change, but I'd have to do it this summer.
或者在这里再坐一年。
Or sit out here another year.
这可能会损失10万人。这可能会导致一场战争。
Which might cost us 100,000 men. It might cost us a war.
这就涉及到他们的主要供应来源，也是我们的眼中钉。
Which brings this talk to their main source of supply - and a thorn in our side.
-牛顿站。 -山姆。
- Newton Station. - Sam.
马洛已经把你计划的细节都搞清楚了。
Marlowe has worked out the details of your plan pretty thoroughly.
如果我能马上回农庄，我们周四就能走了。
If I could get back to La Grange right away, we could leave by Thursday.
很好。你的人马是?
Good. Who would your people be?
我自己的伊利诺斯第一团和西科德的密西根州第一团、爱荷华州第二团。
My own First Illinois with Secord's First Michigan and Second lowa.
我们会被缩减成一个小旅。
We'd be culled down to a short brigade.
穿过La Grange，穿过Ripley, New Albany, Houston…
Cross at La Grange, down through Ripley, New Albany, Houston...
-有什么问题吗，长官?  - 我知道地图。继续。
- Is there something wrong, sir? - I know the map. Proceed.
总之，主要的技巧是在我们到达牛顿站之前不要开战。
Anyway, the main trick is no fighting until we hit Newton Station.
你打算毁掉多少铁轨?
How much track do you figure to destroy?
尽我所能。至少能让他们忙上几个月。
As much as I can. At least enough to keep them busy for a couple of months.
否则，这次突袭只是另一次骑兵行动。
Otherwise, the raid would just be another horse ride.
好吧，上校，说吧。所有的铁轨，枕木，建筑，桥梁，车辆。
All right, Colonel, go ahead. All the rails, ties, buildings, bridges, rolling stock.
山姆，即使他能打通牛顿站，
Sam, even if he should get through to Newton Station,
他会在300英里外的南部邦联腹地
he'd be 300 miles dead centre in the Confederacy.
-你想过怎么回去吗? -你想过吗，长官?
- Have you thought how you'd get back? - Have you, sir?
我想这是我自找的。
Well, I guess I asked for that.
但我不想让你在安德森维尔监狱里坐牢。
But I hate to think of you sitting it out in Andersonville Prison.
-那是个地狱。-我也会仔细考虑的，先生
- It's a hellhole. - I'd think about that twice, too, sir.
上校，祝你成功。
Well, Colonel, your success.
田纳西州拉格兰奇的联邦骑兵兵站
THE UNION CAVALRY DEPOT AT LA GRANGE, TENNESSEE
好了，这里是La Grange。
All right, here is La Grange.
-我们平均每天走35英里。- 35英里吗?
- We will make 35 miles a day, average. - 35?
35英里吗?这是不是有点夸张了?
35? Isn't that stretching it a bit?
这是第一天，奈德。我打算走两倍的距离。
It will be the first day, Ned. I intend to make twice that distance.
在这样的行动中，一切都很紧张。
In an operation like this, everything is stretched.
等一下，约翰。
Now, just hold on a minute, John.
把士兵的口粮从五天削减到三天
Cutting the men's rations from five days to three...
他们最终还是得靠这片土地。他们还是习惯了吧。
They'll have to live off the land eventually. They might as well get used to it.
他们看起来很兴奋。有传言说他们要去纳什维尔阅兵。
They seem excited. There's a rumour they're headed for Nashville and a parade.
在军士长的帮助下，这是一个很好的谣言。
That was a good rumour to spread, with the help of the Sergeant Major.
-谢谢，长官  -先生们
- Thank you, sir. - And, gentlemen,
我得承认他们也把我骗了。
I'll have to admit they had me fooled too.
你看，我本来打算利用我的假期回家做点竞选活动的。
You see, I was going to use my leave to do a little electioneering back home.
你知道，握几个手，亲几个孩子。
You know, shake a few hands, kiss a few babies.
你知道，今年秋天我要竞选国会议员。
You see, I'm running for Congress this fall.
安德森维尔有三万张选票，菲尔。
Well, there's 30,000 votes at Andersonville, Phil.
我希望你别跟他们任何人握手。
I hope you don't get to shake any of their hands.
休假被取消了，命令重新整装，
Leaves are being cancelled, orders to reshoe the whole blasted outfit,
鞋还没擦亮呢。
and some of them shoes ain't even shiny yet.
是的。
Yep.
我在想怎么回事。他们整个早上都在树下坐着。
I'm trying to figure out what's up. They've been sitting under that tree all morning.
我听到一些流言说我们要去北方参加大阅兵。
I heard some scuttlebutt about us being pulled out for a big parade up North.
-我想我们要去纳什维尔。-这正合我意。
- I figure we're heading for Nashville. - That's to my liking.
阅兵，然后离开。现在这场战争开始成形了。
A parade, and then leave. Now this war is starting to shape up.
-军官会议在哪里?  -那边那棵树下，长官。
- Where's the officers' conference? - Over under that tree yonder, sir.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
-我很抱歉迟到了。-理解。
- My apologies for being late. - Understood.
-请坐，少校。-我不认识少校。
- Sit down, Major. - I don't believe I know the Major.
我很抱歉。马洛上校，这是肯德尔少校。
I'm sorry. Colonel Marlowe, Major Kendall.
-你好!  -很高兴认识你。
- How do you do? - Glad to know you.
肯达尔少校刚被格兰特将军派来。
Major Kendall has just been assigned to us by General Grant.
少校好像没穿制服。你的武器呢，肯德尔?
The Major seems to be out of uniform. Where are your side arms, Kendall?
如果你看一下这本书，你会发现外科医生不带它们。
If you look in the book, you'll see a surgeon doesn't carry them.
外科医生?你切断了我们的火炮和马车。没什么能让我们慢下来。
Surgeon? You cut out our artillery and our wagons. Nothing to slow us down.
现在你又给我们安排了医生和医疗队?
And now you saddle us with a doctor and a medical unit?
规定,约翰。肯德尔也去。
Regulations, John. Kendall goes along.
很好，先生。有什么问题吗?
Very well, sir. Any questions?
-我只能说我很高兴能有所行动。-没有荣耀狩猎。
- All I can say is I'm glad for some action. - No glory hunting.
如果有什么能让这一切变得有意义，那就是一场交火。就这些吗，先生?
If anything knocks this into a cocked hat, it'll be a firefight. Is that all, sir?
-洛根，布雷迪准备好了吗? -哦，一张照片。
- Logan, is Brady ready? - Oh, a photograph.
离开。向后移动。
Move away. Move back.
准备好了吗，布雷迪?
Are you ready for us, Brady?
上校。请坐，上校。
Colonel. Sit down, Colonel.
-非常感谢。-没关系。
- Thank you very much. - That's all right.
-坐下，马洛。-请不要戴帽子，先生们。
- Sit down, Marlowe. - No hats, please, gentlemen.
这是正确的。很好，很放松。
That's right. Nice and relaxed.
现在，玫瑰是红色的，紫罗兰是蓝色的，摄像机正对着你。
Now, roses are red, violets are blue, the camera's looking straight at you.
哦，我必须再来一个。那个穿白大褂的人动了一下。
Oh, I must have another one. That man in the white coat moved.
这还不是他不久之后要搬走的全部。将军，就这些吗?
That isn't all he'll be moving before long. General, is that all?
就这样，先生们。谢谢你，布雷迪。
That's all, gentlemen. Thank you, Brady.
谢谢你，将军。非常感谢。
Thank you, General. Thank you very much.
坐下来。
Sit down.
上校，我知道你对我的参与不太满意。
Colonel, I gather you're not too happy about my going along.
我没指望你，仅此而已。
I hadn't counted on you, that's all.
从战术上讲，我能理解你想避免战斗的原因。
I can understand your reasons for trying to avoid a fight, tactically speaking.
但你要深入敌人领地了。
But you're going very deep into enemy territory.
告诉我，你打算怎么处理你的伤员?
Tell me, what did you intend to do about your wounded?
我要行动，而且要快。
I intend to move, and move fast.
那些因枪伤过重而无法继续战斗的人将被留给敌人宽恕。
Those too badly shot up to carry on will be left to the clemency of the enemy.
-平民或军方。-包括你自己?
- Civilian or military. - Including yourself?
自然。
Naturally.
这是一种非常原始的态度。从医学上来讲。
That's a pretty primitive attitude. Medically speaking.
医生，战争并不是什么文明的事。
Well, Doctor, war isn't exactly a civilised business.
当然，我意识到这给了你们更广阔的机会……
Of course, I realise that it gives you fellas a wider field of opportunity...
-为了试验，上校 ?-我可没这么说
- For experimenting, Colonel? - I didn't say that.
-米奇。-什么事，长官?
- Mitch. - Yes, sir?
-给医生一份完整的名册。-是的，长官。
- Give the doctor a full roster. - Yes, sir.
各人要察验。
Examine every man.
把任何不称职的人-当然，以你毫无异议的观点-都赶出去。
Throw out any man who - in your unchallenged opinion, of course - is unfit.
甚至是那些一周后可能会生病的人。
Even those who might get sick a week from today.
听着，这次任务不是我要求的。
Look, I didn't ask to be assigned to this mission.
我是军医。我接到命令要去，我要做好我的工作。
I'm a military doctor. I've been ordered to go and I'm going to do my job.
所以别再烦我了。
So get off my back.
-号手!  -什么事，长官?
- Bugler! - Yes, sir?
-给我接米奇尔 -米切尔军士长在医院
- Get me Mitchell. - Sergeant Major Mitchell's in the hospital.
-你多大了? - 32，长官。
- How old are you? - 32, sir.
加入那个团体。
Join that group.
坚持住，孩子。开始吧。
Hang on, son. Here we go.
(大喊)
(yells)
(金属当啷声)
(metal clanks)
这样会更疼。
This is going to hurt worse.
在那里。他会没事的。
There. He'll be all right.
-我拿到你的病单了，肯德尔  -好。我很高兴它很短。
- I got your sick list, Kendall. - Good. I'm glad it's a short one.
我们把它都去掉。
We'll let that drain full out.
-我同意，医生。-这孩子长了个疖子。
- I approve of that, Doctor. - The lad had quite a boil.
我不是来看你在别人屁股上刻字的。
I didn't come here to watch you carving anybody's behind.
-为什么米奇尔的名字在名单上? -长官，请保持安静。
- Why's Mitchell's name on that list? - Sir, we observe quiet here.
-这是什么? -霍比，这是马洛上校。
- What's this? - Hoppy, this is Colonel Marlowe.
你好!列队。我们马上就来照顾你。
How do you do? Stand in line. We'll take care of you presently.
-他和我们一起去吗? -他是个好人。我需要他。
- Is he going with us? - He's a good man. I need him.
-我需要米奇尔他壮得像头公牛。-我给你看样东西。
- I need Mitchell. He's strong as a bull. - Let me show you something.
上校，我一直在跟医生说这没什么不正常的。
Colonel, I've been trying to tell the doctor that this is nothing unusual.
对一个有疟疾的人来说不是。
Not for a man with malaria.
这不是什么新鲜事，肯德尔。
There's nothing new about this, Kendall.
我见过他一天骑40英里，浑身发抖。
I've seen him ride 40 miles in one day, shivering.
-他总是得疟疾。-所以你同意我的诊断。
- He always gets malaria. - So you concur in my diagnosis.
米奇，起床。我买了些威士忌。
Mitch, get out of bed. I got some whiskey.
你待在原地别动，中士。
You stay where you are, Sergeant.
我接到命令，把我认为不称职的人从值勤名册上除名。
I was ordered to take off the duty roster any man who in my opinion was unfit.
他病了，要留在这里。这是我的命令。
He's sick and he's going to stay here. Those are my orders.
你已经读完整本书了，是吗?
You've read the whole book, haven't you?
(踢桶)
(kicks buckets)
哦,上校!
Oh, Colonel!
我们帮你抓到了那个满身条纹的家伙。
We got that fella with all them stripes for you.
-把他带进来。-我们把他从火车上拖下来了
- Bring him in. - We hauled him right off the train.
-柯比中士报道，长官  -哦，柯比
- Sergeant Kirby reporting, sir. - Well, Kirby.
除了喝醉了，还有什么让你生气的?
Besides being drunk, what's got you riled up?
他们让我进城了。把我拉下火车。
They got me in town. Pulled me off the train.
刚灌满酒。两年来的第一次。
Just gotten filled. My first in two years.
他们告诉我你很棒。你很不错。
They tell me you're good. You better be.
你要取代全团最好的士兵。
You're replacing the best soldier in the regiment.
-我希望你对此感到高兴。-我去的地方会更快乐。
- I expect you to be happy about that. - I could be happier where I was going.
-你说对了。-不，先生，是你让我来的。
- You got me there. - No, sir, you got me here.
-长官  -长官
- Sir. - Sir.
把这个中士扔到河里。
March this sergeant to the river and throw him in.
-衣服和所有? -衣服和所有。
- Clothes and all? - Clothes and all.
给他灌满黑咖啡直到他耳朵里都流出来。
Pump him full of black coffee till it runs out his ears.
柯比，你回来的时候，一定要清醒。你有两个小时。
Kirby, when you come back, come back sober. You've got two hours.
-阅兵，纳什维尔…  -你可以把那桶留下。
- Parades, Nashville... - You can leave that keg.
你不用客气……先生。
You're welcome to it... sir.
跟我纠缠，我就把你扒光。
Tangle with me and I'll have your hide.
不客气，先生，如果这是你的职责范围的话。
You're welcome to that too, sir. If it's in the line of duty.
(喇叭)
( bugle)
-向前，向左转!  -(其他人)向前，向左转!
- Forward, left! - (others) Forward, left!
-Yo-oh !-(其他人)哟!
- Yo-oh! - (others) Yo-oh!
我离开了我的爱，我的爱，我离开了，睡在她的床上
(male choir) I left my love My love I left, a-sleeping in her bed
我背弃了我的真爱去和叛军作战
I turned my back on my true love Went fighting Johnny Reb
我给我的爱人留了一封信在树洞里…
I left my love a letter in the holler of a tree...
-祝你好运，约翰。-谢谢，长官。
- Good luck, John. - Thank you, sir.
嗨，他们走了，没有“不能”这个词
Hi-ho, down they go There's no such word as "can't"
我们会直奔地狱然后回来找尤利西斯·辛普森·格兰特
We'll ride clean down to hell and back for Ulysses Simpson Grant
我给我的爱人留了一封信在树洞里
I left my love a letter in the holler of a tree
我告诉她，她会在美国骑兵队找到我
I told her she would find me in the US Cavalry
美国骑兵
In the US Cavalry
嗨，他们走了，没有“不能”这个词
Hi-ho, down they go There's no such word as "can't"
我们直接去新奥尔良
We'll ride clean down to New Orleans
献给尤利西斯·辛普森·格兰特
For Ulysses Simpson Grant
我离开了我的爱我的爱我离开了
I left my love My love I left
睡在她的床上
A-sleeping in her bed
在这儿等一会儿。
Wait on here a minute.
-太阳每次都从东方升起?  -在密苏里州确实如此。
- The sun, it raises in the east every time? - It sure does in Missouri.
八小时了，我们一直朝这个方向走，没有转弯。
For eight hours, with no turning, we've been heading this way.
如果太阳从东方升起，那是哪个方向?
If the sun raises in the east, what direction is that?
-这不是北方。-当然不是。这是南方。
- It ain't north. - Course not. It's south.
我们正好进入了叛军的地盘。
We've been riding smack-dab into reb territory.
-叛军的地盘，理查德。 -是的，先生。
- Reb country, Richard. - Yes, sir.
派出你的侦察兵。
Send out your scouts.
(大叫顺序)
(yells order)
(枪声)
(gunfire)
你是叫他们停下来呢，还是让敌人宽恕他们呢?
Are you going to call a halt, or leave them to the clemency of the enemy?
吹号撤回。
Sound recall.
(喇叭)
( bugle)
只是巡逻队，长官，据我所知，没有任何主力部队的踪迹。
Just a patrol, sir. No sign of any major force, as far as I could tell.
事实是我们被发现了。
The fact remains we've been spotted.
现在消息已经传出去了。他们会带着所有可用的东西回来的。
The word's out for sure now. They'll be back here with everything available.
好了，内德，你可以准备回去了。
All right, Ned, you can prepare to turn back.
这是个严重的错误，约翰，分散兵力。
That's a bad mistake, John, splitting the force.
现在你需要所有人手。该死的转移。
Now you need every man you've got. Diversion be damned.
-他们会以为我们都回去了。-当然，当然。
- They've got to think we all turned back. - Oh, sure, sure.
但从现在起，所有拿着枪的印第安人都要躲在树后面
But from now on, every Johnny Reb with a gun will be hiding behind a tree
想要扬名立万。
trying to make a name for himself.
而你想把你的部队削减三分之一!约翰，听我说。
And you want to cut your force by one third! John, listen to me.
在政治上有一个古老的公理:你永远不要分开你的选票……
There's an old axiom in politics: You never split your ballot...
理查德，等马喝好水，人吃饱了，我们就出发。
Richard, when the horses are watered and the men are fed, we'll move out.
嘿,医生。
Hey, Doctor.
这些走私来的孩子说小木屋有问题。
These here contraband children say there's something wrong at that cabin.
我想他们需要一个医生。
I guess they need a doctor.
好吧。
All right.
-你是医生吗?-是的，我是。
- Are you the doctor? - Yes, I am.
发生了什么事?
What happened?
是雷尼，先生，雷尼是第一个。他死了。
It's Rainey, sir. Rainey the first. He's dead.
继续工作。
Carry on.
肯德尔在哪?
Where's Kendall?
肯德尔医生和一些年轻的有色人种一起去了那间小屋。
Dr Kendall went over to that cabin with some young coloured people.
-我想是紧急情况  -他什么?!
- An emergency, I believe. - He what?!
他和一些年轻的有色人种一起去了那间小屋。
He went over to that cabin with some young coloured people.
-你也是医生吗?  -什么?不,不。
- Are you the doctor too? - What? No, no.
(哭)
(baby cries)
肯德尔，你在搞什么鬼?
Kendall, what the devil are you doing?
我们刚接生了一个孩子。
We just delivered a baby.
是个小女孩。
It's a little girl.
你现在可以照顾她了，奶奶。
You can take care of her now, Granny.
你会没事的。
You're going to be all right.
外面有几个人受伤了，你知道的。
We've got a couple of wounded men out there, you know.
不，有一个死了。
No, one's dead.
一个走了，一个出生了。
One's gone, one's born.
这是一个神奇的过程，不是吗?
It's an amazing process, isn't it?
虽然我接生了很多次，但我总是感到敬畏。
As many as I've delivered, it never fails to awe me.
好了，孩子们，你们有新妹妹了。进去，看看她。
All right, children, you got a new sister. Go in, take a look at her.
好吧，肯德尔。回去照顾你的伤员吧。
All right, Kendall. Go back and take care of your wounded.
他们会没事的。霍普金斯知道该怎么做。
They'll be all right. Hopkins knows what to do.
你不是乡巴佬。你是一名宣过誓的联邦军队军官。
You're not a country sawbones. You're an officer in the Union Army under oath.
在那之前我发过一个更古老的誓言。
I took an older oath before that one.
他们以前在这附近生孩子似乎没有什么困难。
They didn't seem to be having any trouble having babies around here before.
他们请我帮忙，我不能拒绝他们。别胡扯了。甚至你出生了。
I was asked to help and I couldn't turn 'em down. Come off it. Even you were born.
现在，你已经被军官逮捕了。
As of now, you are under officer's arrest.
不服从。
Insubordination.
-我还履行我的职责吗，先生? -从现在开始把他们关在部队里。
- Do I still carry out my duties, sir? - From now on confine them to the troops.
很好，先生。
Very well, sir.
别逼我太紧，肯德尔。
Don't push me too far, Kendall.
前进!
Forward!
(狗吠)
(dogs bark)
卢姬，狗狗们为什么这么大惊小怪?
Lukey, what are the dogs raising such a fuss about?
狗?你知道狗有多大惊小怪。
Dogs? You know how dogs make such a fuss.
-士兵，汉娜小姐。很多人  -士兵?多么美妙!
- Soldiers, Miss Hannah. Lots of 'em. - Soldiers? How wonderful!
屋外的雷声。他们的北方佬。
Thunder in the outhouse. Them's Yankees.
卢姬，你下楼去见他们。
Lukey, you go on downstairs and meet them.
卢姬，你听见了吗?
Lukey, do you hear?
过来，姑娘。
Come here, girl.
来吧。
Come on.
-谁住在这里?  -汉娜·亨特小姐住在这里。
- Who lives here? - Miss Hannah Hunter lives here.
告诉她我想见她。马洛上校，联邦军。
Tell her I want to see her. Colonel Marlowe, Union Army.
是的,先生。
Yes, sir.
把枪收起来。
Put that gun away.
-抱歉打扰了，女士  -不是那样的，上校
- Sorry for this intrusion, ma'am. - It isn't that, Colonel.
只是我从没想过会在这屋子里看到那身制服。
It's just that I never prepared myself to see that uniform within the walls of this house.
女士，我们不希望待在这里就像你不希望我们待在这里一样。
Ma'am, we no more wish to be here than you do to have us.
上校，你说得真好。
Why, that's gallantly spoken, Colonel.
不管我们有多大的不同，我担心我忘记了舒适的生活。
No matter what our differences, I fear I'm forgetting the amenities.
-欢迎来到绿蔷薇，先生们  -谢谢。
- Welcome to Greenbriar, gentlemen. - Thank you.
卢姬，拿上男士们的帽子。
Lukey, take the gentlemen's hats.
-柯比中士。-中士。
- Sergeant Kirby. - Sergeant.
女士。
Ma'am.
好吧，我们把玫瑰屋弄得舒服点吗?
Well, shall we make ourselves more comfortable in the Rose Room?
不用了，谢谢你，女士。我们只待一会儿。
No, thank you, ma'am. We'll only stay a moment.
你和你的人要继续前进吗?
You and your men are riding on?
不，我们会在你的树林里过夜。
No, we will bivouac in your woods for the night.
睡在冰冷的地面上?
Sleeping on the cold, cold ground?
这场糟糕、浪费、可怕的斗争什么时候才能结束，上校?
When is this awful, wasteful, terrible struggle going to end, Colonel?
兄弟对抗兄弟……
Brother against brother...
在我们逗留期间，任何人都不允许离开这里。
And during our stay no one will be allowed to leave the premises.
我们能去哪里，上校?
Wherever would we go, Colonel?
我相信你一定同意，这场战争让每个人都感到孤独。
I'm sure you must agree that this war makes loneliness for everyone.
还有，我必须征用大部分的粮食和马匹，如果你有的话。
Also, I must commandeer most of the grain and horses, if you have any.
亨特小姐，你的所有东西，都用联邦的美钞偿还。
You will be paid, Miss Hunter, for everything, in Union greenbacks.
我们不会再打扰你了。晚上好。
We will not bother you any longer. Good evening.
-科比。-请原谅，女士。
- Kirby. - By your leave, ma'am.
汉娜·亨特，你怎么了，说话像个干农活的?你们所有人，我们所有人。
Hannah Hunter, what's got hold of you, talking like a field hand? You alls, we alls.
北方佬!
Yankees!
真不可思议，上校。
It's uncanny, Colonel.
我听说过他们，但我不相信。
I've heard about 'em, but I didn't believe it.
我接受了密歇根州长的委任!
I received my commission from the Governor of Michigan!
-年轻人…  -你的问题是什么?
- Young man... - What's your question?
问题是这个人在他现在职务上的权威。
The question is this man's authority in his present position.
像往常一样，我试图呈现生活的残酷事实。
As usual, I am trying to present the grim facts of life.
他不明白如果厕所是在下游而不是上游挖的
He doesn't understand that coffee tastes better
咖啡更好喝。
if the latrines are dug downstream instead of upstream.
你要什么样的咖啡，上校?
How do you like your coffee, Colonel?
-西科德，你应该…  -请原谅。
- Secord, you oughta... - Pardon.
上校!马洛上校!
Colonel! Colonel Marlowe!
我忘记了我的礼仪。哎呀，我怎么会……
I am forgetting my manners. Why, how I ever...
我想我没见过这两位先生。
Well, I don't believe I've met these gentlemen.
亨特小姐。西科德上校。格雷少校。肯德尔少校。
Miss Hunter. Colonel Secord. Major Gray. Major Kendall.
女士。
Ma'am.
我只是太浮躁了。
I'm just so scatterbrained.
可怜的爸爸妈妈一定在坟墓里为我翻来覆去
Poor Papa and Mama must be turning over in their graves at me
绿蔷薇所能提供的一点款待都没有
for not extending what little hospitality Greenbriar can offer.
至少我可以邀请你们共进晚餐。
At least I can extend an invitation to you for dinner.
-不，亨特小姐…  -我坚持。
- No, Miss Hunter... - I insist.
有三只肥阉鸡无论如何都得享用。
There's three fat capons that have to go anyhow.
就像你说的，我们的粮食储备减少了。
What with our store of grain being reduced, like you mentioned.
你看，这是你自找的，不是吗?
So, you see, you brought it on yourself, didn't you?
就我个人而言，我很高兴……
Speaking for myself, I would be delighted...
很好，谢谢。好的食物很难拒绝。
Very well, thank you. Hot food is pretty hard to turn down.
太好的。现在，我预计有几个客人?
Splendid. Now, how many can I count on?
-五个还是六个…?  -别客气。
- Would five or six be...? - Not at all.
太棒了。
Perfectly wonderful.
九点，先生们?
At nine, gentlemen?
-西科德上校? -密歇根第一团的，女士
- Colonel Secord? - Of the First Michigan, ma'am.
-格雷少校?  -女士。
- Major Gray? - Ma'am.
主要…肯德尔，对吧?
Major... Kendall, isn't it?
我恐怕要爽约，女士。我向你保证，这不是我的选择。
I'm afraid I'll have to regret, ma'am. It's not of my choice, I assure you.
刚才，我被逮捕了。
At the moment, I'm under arrest.
我们都很乐意接受邀请，亨特小姐。
We will all be glad to accept the invitation, Miss Hunter.
女士吗?
Ma'am?
你的手帕掉了。
You dropped your handkerchief.
-想再来点吗，西科德上校?  -不用了，谢谢你，女士
- Care for a little more, Colonel Secord? - No, thank you, ma'am.
马洛上校?
Colonel Marlowe?
-不用了，谢谢。-来吧，上校。
- No, thank you. - Come now, Colonel.
像你这么魁梧的人不能像山雀一样一点点吃下去。
A man with a big frame like yours can't just nibble away like a little old titmouse.
先生们，请坐。
Gentlemen, please be seated.
你的偏好是什么?腿……还是胸?
Now, what was your preference? The leg... or the breast?
这两样我都吃够了，谢谢。
I've had quite enough of both, thank you.
真可惜。
What a shame.
-还有人想再来点吗?  -不用了，谢谢。
- Would anyone else like some more? - (all) No, thank you.
先生们，请坐。我也得提醒你，这里没有咖啡了。
Gentlemen, be seated. I must warn you too, there's no coffee.
任何种类的甜食或甜点都是不可能的。
And a sweet or a dessert of any kind was just out of the question.
糖是150美元一桶。
Sugar's $150 a barrel.
“然而你的美言却像糖一样甜，
"And yet your fair discourse hath been as sweet as sugar,
让艰难的过程变得甜蜜和美味。”
making the hard way sweet and delectable."
多么迷人啊。你自己的东西?
How perfectly charming. A little something of your own?
不,女士。理查德二世。
No, ma'am. Richard II.
-我的职业是演员。-啊，真有意思!
- By profession, I'm an actor. - Why, how fascinating!
为什么，肯德尔少校，你的雪茄。先生们，请坐。
Why, Major Kendall, your cigar. Gentlemen, please be seated.
(叹息)
(sighs)
肯德尔少校是医生。西科德上校差点成为国会议员。
Major Kendall a doctor. And Colonel Secord almost a congressman.
你是个演员。现在都是军人。
And you an actor. And now all military men.
真是浪费人才。
Such a waste of talent.
不过，马洛上校，我想你应该是个职业军人吧。
But, of course, Colonel Marlowe, I imagine that you are a professional soldier.
不，在这之前，我是个铁路工程师。
No, prior to this insanity, I was a railroad engineer.
啊，真令人激动。
Why, how thrilling.
想想看，能驾驶这么大的东西，冒着热气。
To think of being able to steer one of those huge things, puffing and steaming.
按那个小铃铛。叮咚!叮咚!
Ringing that little bell. Ding-dong! Ding-dong!
不完全是。我的工作是修建铁路。
Not quite. My job was in the construction of railroads.
为什么,我的天!如此聪明的头脑。
Why, my! Such brilliant minds.
可怜的我勉强从朗斯特里特小姐女子神学院毕业。
Poor little me barely squeezed through Miss Longstreet's Seminary for Ladies.
你上大学时是怎么记住那么多书的?
How did you ever manage to remember all those books in college?
我没有。我开始以每天十美分的工资开铁钉，然后发现。
I didn't. I started driving rail spikes at ten cents a day and found.
现在，亨特小姐，我必须请你离开。
And now, Miss Hunter, I must ask you to leave us.
我们有幸借用这个房间一两个小时。如果可以的话。
We are taking the privilege of using this room for an hour or two. If we may.
当然可以，但是你不想用另一个房间吗?也许是研究?
Of course, but wouldn't you prefer using another room? The study, perhaps?
-我们在这里很舒服。 -(低声表示同意)
- We're quite comfortable here. - (murmurs of agreement)
对不起，我必须粗鲁地解释一下。
I'm sorry but I must be rude and explain.
卢姬和我必须在早上五点前赶到地里。
Lukey and I must be in the fields by five in the morning.
先生们，去点雪茄吧。
Gentlemen, go ahead and light your cigars.
-让我来。-谢谢你。
- Allow me. - Thank you kindly.
在她上床睡觉之前，所有这些和碗都必须洗好。
All this and the dishes must be done before she can get to bed.
-我太不体谅人了吗?  -当然不是，女士。
- Am I being too inconsiderate? - Of course not, ma'am.
-我可以吗?  -当然。这边走，先生们。
- May I? - Of course. This way, gentlemen.
多么美妙。
How wonderful.
真的，我觉得这顿晚餐很迷人。
Really, I thought it was a charming dinner.
-这个房间设岗。 -是的，长官。
- Post this room. - Yes, sir.
-我希望你在这里过得舒服。 -哦，是的。这很好。
- I hope you'll be comfortable here. - Oh, yes. This is fine.
-如果你想生火，已经准备好了。-不，没关系。
- If you wish to light a fire, it's ready. - No, it's fine.
-白兰地。我叫卢姬拿来。-不，谢谢，不喝白兰地。
- Some brandy. I'll have Lukey bring it. - No, thank you, no brandy.
你确定我不能再…
Are you sure there's nothing more that I can...
哦,是的。
Oh, yes.
医生，你没必要掺和进来。
Doctor, there's no need for you to be a part of this.
也许亨特小姐会带你去看看绿蔷薇的美景。
Perhaps Miss Hunter would show you some of the beauties of Greenbriar.
-当然，如果他有兴趣的话…  -他很乐意。
- Why, of course, if he has any interest... - He'd be pleased to.
很好。那么，来吧，医生。
Very well. Come, then, Doctor.
我注意到一个可爱的花园。我们去散散步好吗?
I noticed a lovely garden. Shall we take a stroll?
当然了。
Why, of course.
先生们，你们必须穿着厚重的制服，
You know, you gentlemen must be comfortable in your heavy uniforms,
但我确实感到空气中有一股寒意——那是我和我那稀薄的血液。
but I feel a definite chill in the air - it's me and my thin blood.
对不起，我去拿一条披肩。
Would you excuse me while I go and fetch a shawl?
-亨特小姐。-什么事，少校?
- Miss Hunter. - Yes, Major?
恐怕我得和你一起去。
I'm afraid I'll have to go with you.
楼上吗?和我在一起吗?
Upstairs? With me?
-为什么，少校!  -你只得到一条披肩。
- Why, Major! - You're only getting a shawl.
当然，但在这些地方，这是闻所未闻的…
Of course, but in these parts it's unheard of...
这是要告诉你的孙子孙女的事情。
It's something to tell your grandchildren.
这是战争。目前，绿蔷薇是一个军事设施。
This is war. At the moment, Greenbriar is a military installation.
我想不会有什么真正的伤害，因为你是个医生。
I don't suppose there's any real harm, being that you're a doctor.
这是正确的。
That's right.
卢姬，请拿点白兰地到我的客厅来。
Lukey, bring some brandy to my sitting room, please.
-我希望你在这里过得舒服，少校。 -谢谢。
- I hope you'll be comfortable here, Major. - Thank you.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
嘿!你拿着它要去哪里?
Hey! Where are you going with that?
-汉娜小姐要的白兰地。 -我知道，为了少校
- Miss Hannah asked for this brandy. - I know, for the Major.
我们从不给我们的高级军官一瓶没有标签的酒，
We never give any of our top-ranking officers an unlabelled bottle,
除非有人先尝一下。
unless somebody tastes it first.
-这就是你的工作吗?测试的东西? -当然。
- Is this what you does? Test things? - Certainly.
看到第二条条纹了吗?也就是说我是以上专业的正式试吃员。
See that second stripe? That means I'm official taster for majors on up.
这是La Grange。
Here's La Grange.
我们南下了大约80英里。
We've come down here approximately 80 miles.
-我们要去牛顿站。 -那边的敌人兵力有消息吗?
- We're headed for Newton Station. - Any word on the enemy strength there?
没有，一点消息也没有。不管怎么样，我们都有义务承担。
No, not a word. Whatever it is, we're obliged to take it on.
-好。也许我们会看到行动。 -这不是演戏。
- Good. Maybe we'll see action. - This is not play-acting.
-先生，这是您的白兰地  -谢谢
- Here's your brandy, sir. - Oh, thank you.
-都经过测试了。-测试?
- It's all tested. - Tested?
楼下那个穿着测试服条纹的男人，在上面。
By the man downstairs with those tester's stripes, for majors on up.
哦,是的。柯比中士。
Oh, yes. Sergeant Kirby.
-他真的测试过了，不是吗?  -是的，先生，两次。
- He really tested it, didn't he? - Yes, sir. Twice.
-卢姬 ?-是的，汉娜小姐。
- Lukey? - Yes, Miss Hannah.
对不起，先生。
Excuse me, sir.
(马洛)…很幸运。
(Marlowe)... very lucky.
(军官的声音)
(officers' voices)
这是下一条信息。我们不回拉格兰奇了。
That is the next piece of information. We're not going back to La Grange.
-我们什么? -我们不回北方了
- We're what? - We're not going back north.
我们向南前往巴吞鲁奇，在那里与联邦军队会合。
We're heading south to Baton Rouge to join up with the Union forces there.
-天哪，你什么时候决定的? -这是最好的办法。这是唯一的办法。
- Great Scott, when did you decide that? - It's the best way. It's the only way.
约翰，从牛顿站到巴吞鲁奇有300英里。
John, it is 300 miles from Newton Station to Baton Rouge.
从牛顿站到拉格兰奇有300英里。
And it is 300 miles from Newton Station to La Grange.
只有叛军真正在我们身后，准备把我们嚼成碎片。
Only the rebs will really have been closed in behind us, ready to chew us to bits.
所以我们要从他们最意想不到的方向出发:一直向南。
So we'll go out the way they least expect: Straight south.
该死，这是自杀。有没有可能你的命令被误解了?
Damn it, it's suicide. Is it possible your orders could have been misinterpreted?
牛顿站之后我唯一的任务
My only duty after Newton Station
就是尽可能多地把这些人活着救回来
is to get as many of these men back alive as I can.
(西科德)所以我还是要抗议。
(Secord) And so I still must protest.
更重要的是，我要把这事记录在案，交给赫尔伯特将军。
What's more, I want that on the record for General Hurlburt.
这是鲁莽的集体自杀。
It is impetuous mass suicide.
这是记录在案的，但听听这个。
(Marlowe) It's on the record, but get this.
除非敌人允许你取代我的位置，否则就只能这样了。
Unless enemy action allows you to take my place, that's the way it will be.
把牛顿站从地图上弄走，然后去巴吞鲁奇。
Blow Newton Station off the map, then through to Baton Rouge.
不会有任何改变。你明白吗?
There will be no change. Do you understand?
(西科德)好吧，你来指挥。
(Secord) All right, you're in command.
(马洛)现在我们再复习一遍。直达巴吞鲁奇。
(Marlowe) Now let's go over it again. Straight through to Baton Rouge.
我们不会回头。
We will not turn back.
抱歉让你久等了。白兰地令人满意吗?
Sorry for keeping you waiting. Was the brandy satisfactory?
-好。你不和我一起去吗?  -天哪，没有。我从来不碰鬼魂。
- Excellent. Won't you join me? - Goodness me, no. I never touch spirits.
我爸爸教我，一个女孩应该时刻保持头脑清醒。
My papa taught me that a girl ought to keep her wits about her at all times.
你父亲养育了一个非常聪明的女儿。
Your father raised a very smart girl.
你太贴心了。你想看看花园吗?
You're being sweet. Would you like to see the garden?
你忘了带披肩吗?
Didn't you forget your shawl?
怎么了,卢姬 !
Why, Lukey!
现在，卢姬，你把盘子拿下楼去做你该做的事。
Now, Lukey, you take that tray downstairs and go about doing what you have to do.
我记得我第一次喝烈酒的时候，在杰克逊的州长舞会上。
You know, I remember the first time I tried spirits, at the Governor's Ball in Jackson.
我的男伴，比洛克西的亚当·拉芙莱斯，他给了我一杯薄荷朱利酒。
My escort, Adam Lovelace from Biloxi, well, he gave me a mint julep.
你知道的，那些拉芙莱斯男孩都很帅，但是速度很快，
You know, those Lovelace boys are all very handsome, but fast,
如果你明白我的意思。
if you know what I mean.
如果我能告诉你那杯酒之后我脑子里的想法……我的天!
If I could tell you the thoughts that went on in my mind after that one julep... My!
我更想知道你现在脑子里在想什么。
I'd rather know the thoughts going on in your mind right now.
-肯德尔，你到底在说什么?  -抱歉，我们得打断一下。
- Kendall, what in the name of...? - Sorry we have to interrupt.
问问他们你的机会有多大
Ask them what they think your chances are
炸了牛顿车站然后去巴吞鲁奇
of blowing up Newton Station and getting to Baton Rouge.
-你喝醉了吗?  -不幸的是，没有。
- Are you drunk? - Unfortunately, no.
他们在楼上听着。
They were listening upstairs.
这是个很好的听诊器。
Makes a pretty good stethoscope.
不要感到内疚。我也不太明白。
Don't feel guilty. I was slow to catch on too.
你去哪儿了，肯德尔?
Where were you, Kendall?
绅士在偷看女士的卧室前要三思，
Well, a gentlemen thinks twice before peeking into a lady's bedroom,
但有时它是有回报的。
but sometimes it pays off.
看来她把我们俩都耍了。
Looks like she's made a fool out of both of us.
叮咚。叮咚。
Ding-dong. Ding-dong.
你知道吗，亨特小姐?
You know something, Miss Hunter?
你给我添了不少麻烦。
You have put me to quite an inconvenience.
至少我有所成就，先生。
At least I've accomplished something, sir.
我想我不能接受你不跟任何人讨论这件事的承诺。
I don't suppose I could accept your word of honour not to discuss this with anyone.
-我对任何一个北方佬都不尊敬。-没错。
- I don't hold to honour with any Yankees. - Exactly.
所以整个密西西比州都要警惕了。
So the whole state of Mississippi will be alerted.
所以你能建议我该怎么处置你吗?
So could you possibly suggest what I should do with you?
我注意到她让你心烦了。现在是你射杀她的机会。
I noticed she was getting on your nerves. Now's your chance to shoot her.
-你再多说一个字…  -来吧。杀了我们。
- One more word out of you... - Go ahead. Shoot us.
杀了我们俩。
Shoot both of us.
但你永远也逃不掉你肮脏的谋杀计划，马洛上校。
But you'll never get away with your filthy, murdering plans, Mr Colonel Marlowe.
你们北方佬，还有你们拯救联邦的神圣原则。
You Yankees and your holy principle about saving the Union.
你们是掠夺海盗，就是这样。
You're plundering pirates, that's what.
你以为你要去的地方没有邦联军队吗?
You think there's no Confederate army where you're going?
你觉得我们的孩子在这里睡觉吗?
Do you think our boys are asleep down here?
他们会追上你，把你们撕成碎片，
They'll catch up to you and they'll cut you to pieces,
你们这些无名无父的人渣!
you nameless, fatherless scum!
我希望我能在那里看到它。
And I wish I could be there to see it.
如果真的发生了，亨特小姐，你就会。
If it happens, Miss Hunter, you will be.
快点。
Hurry it up.
好吧。
All right.
你是个优秀的骑手，亨特小姐。
You're an excellent rider, Miss Hunter.
有趣的国家，不是吗?
Interesting country, isn't it?
我更感兴趣的是为什么你们这些破坏者没收了我死去父亲的衣服。
I'm more interested in why you vandals confiscated my dead father's clothes.
嗯，是给我们的学员的。
Well, they're for our cadets.
-侦察兵。 -侦察兵!
- Scouts. - Scouts!
你是说间谍吧。
Spies, you mean.
他们不像蛇一样趴着爬，真是个奇迹。
It's a wonder they don't crawl along on their bellies like snakes.
你会知道间谍在这里的下场。
You'll find out what happens to spies down here.
我个人对付间谍的经验有限。我只知道一个。
My personal experience with spies is limited. I've only known one.
你介意吗，少校?我喜欢一个人骑马。
Do you mind, Major? I prefer to ride alone.
女士。
Ma'am.
汉娜小姐!
Miss Hannah!
好了，向前!Yo-oh !
All right, forward! Yo-oh!
回到队伍里，医生。
Back in line, Doctor.
(汉娜尖叫)
(Hannah screams)
-这位女士的内裤快干了。-是的。
- These lady's drawers are almost dry. - Yeah.
你不觉得冷吗?
Aren't you getting chilly?
别告诉我你担心我的健康
Don't tell me you're concerned about my health.
如果我把你的衣服还给你，你能保证不再逃跑吗?
If I give you back your clothes, will you promise not to run away again?
我会的，女士。有一点，骄傲变得不切实际。
I would, ma'am. There's a point where pride becomes impractical.
事实上，如果你能看看自己，我想你会同意的。
Actually, if you could get a look at yourself, I'd think you'd agree.
很好。我确实希望保持健康。
Very well. I do wish to keep my health.
-我不会再逃跑了。 -你发誓?
- I shall not try to run away again. - Your word of honour?
-我发誓。 -对北方佬?
- My word of honour. - To Yankees?
-对北方佬。 -发誓?
- To Yankees. - Cross your heart?
-我向你保证过!  -好吧，卢姬。
- I gave you my word! - All right, Lukey.
帮亨特小姐穿衣服。
Help Miss Hunter with her clothes.
我很高兴你懂事了。你开始让我担心了。
I'm glad you're being sensible. You were beginning to worry me.
-从医学角度来看  -谢谢你，医生。
- From a medical standpoint. - Thank you, Doctor.
我希望我能提供更多的帮助，但你们南方人民有你们自己的帮助。
I wish I could be of further assistance, but you Southern people have your own help.
(Kirby)立正!眼睛看前面!
(Kirby) Attention! Eyes front!
叛军,先生!
Rebs, sir!
跳过河岸。整整一个旅，快来了。
Hopping that riverbank. A full brigade, coming fast.
骑兵，步兵和炮兵，长官，可不是民兵。
Horse, foot and artillery, sir. It ain't militia, neither.
-多远?  -十分钟。
- How far? - Ten minutes.
好了，躲起来，躲到树里去。
All right, get out of sight, get in those trees.
敌人的巡逻队。找个地方躲起来。
Enemy patrol. Take cover and choke up.
-号手! -不是号手，你个白痴!手语信号。
- Bugler! - Not bugler, you idiot! Hand signals.
河对岸有敌人。躲起去。保持安静。
Enemy across the river. Move out. Keep it quiet.
他为什么不站起来战斗呢?他有整整一个旅。
Why doesn't he stand and fight? He's got a full brigade.
(叛军唱《美丽的蓝旗》)
(rebel troops sing "The Bonnie Blue Flag")
(继续歌唱)
(singing continues)
好哇!好哇!为了南方的权利，万岁!
Hurrah! Hurrah! For Southern rights, hurrah!
为美丽的蓝旗欢呼它有一颗星
Hurrah for the Bonnie Blue Flag That bears a single star
好哇!好哇!为了南方的权利，万岁!
Hurrah! Hurrah! For Southern rights, hurrah!
为美丽的蓝旗欢呼它有一颗星
Hurrah for the Bonnie Blue Flag That bears a single star
-(马哼了一声)  -放松。
- (horse snorts) - Take it easy.
别这样，别这样。
Come on, stop it.
(继续歌唱)
(singing continues)
汉娜!
Hannah!
嘿!救命!在这里!
Hey! Help! Over here!
-(闷声尖叫)  -哎哟!
- (muffled scream) - Ouch!
放开你的牙齿!
Let go with those teeth!
-有800人在外面。-去拿点水。
- I've got 800 men out there. - Get some water.
看来河对岸都安全了。
Looks to be all clear across the river.
嗯…
Well...
要多少个男人才能让一个女人安静下来?
How many men does it take to keep one lone female quiet?
上校，犯人想和你谈谈。
Colonel, the prisoner would like a word with you.
什么事，亨特小姐?
Yes, Miss Hunter?
我不是来抱怨你的所作所为的。
I'm not here to complain about what you did.
你认为这是你的责任，你做到了。
It was your duty as you saw it, and you did it.
很抱歉你不得不食言。
I'm sorry you had to break your word.
我向你保证过不逃跑。我不是为了不求救才这么做的。
I gave my word not to run away. I didn't give it not to cry out for assistance.
我想这是有道理的，
I suppose there's a fine point there,
但我也要请你向我保证。
but I have to ask you to give me your word on that too.
我就是这么做的，此时此地。
I do that, here and now.
否则当我指证你的时候，我的下巴就会骨折。
Or I suppose when I testify against you, I'd be handicapped with a broken jaw.
我想是的。还要别的吗，女士?
I'd say so. Anything else, ma'am?
还有一件小事。我在那里的忠实伙伴。
One slight item. My constant companions there.
当然，我不知道北方的情况如何，
I don't know how it is up North, of course,
但在南方，南方女性有时会觉得需要隐私。
but down South there are times when Southern women feel the need for privacy.
你们两个。
You two.
我们互相尊重。非常尊敬，先生。
We was respectful. Real respectful, sir.
你说只要我们能看到她的头顶就没事。
You told us it was all right just as long as we could see the top of her head.
-你告诉他们的?  -嗯…
- You told them that? - Well...
还有一项。
Then there's one more item.
我建议你去看医生。叮咚。叮咚。
I suggest you see a doctor. Ding-dong. Ding-dong.
(枪)
(gunshot)
在那边的谷仓里。来吧。
Over there in that barn. Come on.
(枪声)
(gunshots)
-我们被伏击了，上校  -好吧，把他们抽出来。
- We was bushwhacked, Colonel. - All right, smoke 'em out.
不要开火。
Hold your fire.
你好我们是联盟军，但我们不是敌人。
Hey, there! We're Confederates, but we ain't hostile.
-诚实的!  -放下武器，出来。
- Honest! - Drop your weapons and come on out.
是的,先生。
Yes, sir.
来了。
Coming.
维吉尔，来吧。
Hey, Virgil, come ahead on.
它们是真正的蓝腹鱼。
They's real bluebellies.
小心点，上校。
Watch it, Colonel.
只有我们两个，上尉，还有一个俘虏。
Just the two of us, Cap. And one captive.
你好，上尉，杰基·乔和我很抱歉突然出现在你们面前。
Howdy, Cap. Jackie Jo and me is sorry about popping away at you people.
我们以为你们更像是治安官的副手。
We thought you was more sheriff's deputies.
你对副警长有什么意见?
What have you got against sheriff's deputies?
-这是个好主意，是吧?  -这是一个狡猾的问题。
- That's a good one, huh? - That's a slick one.
我们就是喜欢治安官。
We just love sheriff's deputies.
他们是南部联盟的逃兵，长官，最劣等的猪。
They're deserters from the Confederacy, sir. The lowest swine bred.
-我猜你是警长吧?  -亨利·古德迪警长，退休了。
- I take it you're the sheriff? - Captain Henry Goodbody, retired.
洛雷纳县代理警长。
Acting sheriff of Lorena County.
我正要逮捕这些老鼠……
I was about to apprehend these rats...
但我们打了你，你这老山羊，不是吗?
But we bushwhacked you, you old goat, didn't we?
是我们做的，杰基·乔。但告诉他们我们的事，古迪约警长。
(Virgil) That we did, Jackie Jo. But tell them about us, Captain Goodyo.
-你敢再碰他! -亨特小姐。
- Don't you dare touch him again! - Miss Hunter.
你!你称自己为男人?和那个人渣一起治疗?
You! You call yourself a man? Treating with that scum?
亨特小姐，那个人是我们的敌人。
Miss Hunter, that man is our enemy.
你敢说一句话，他就会被枪毙。明白吗?
One word from you of any kind and he will be shot. Understand?
没错，队长。
That's right, Cap.
-小姐，需要帮忙吗?  -我完全有能力自己应付。
- Can I help you, miss? - I'm quite capable of getting on by myself.
看来你需要点关注。医生!你能听听我们好朋友的耳朵吗?
Seems you need a little attention. Doctor! Will you look to our good friend's ear?
对不起，我胃不好。奥蒂斯，看看你能为我们的新兵做些什么。
Sorry but I got a weak stomach. Otis, see what you can do for our new recruit.
很难解释一个男人，不是吗?
Hard to explain a man, isn't it?
照顾好这个人。
Take care of this man.
枪伤，长官。
Gunshot wound, sir.
噢!你打算把那东西插到对岸去吗?
Ow! You aim to stick that thing clear through to the other side?
我非常怀疑它会遇到任何阻碍。
I seriously doubt it would have met with any obstruction.
中士，给我来两支上等雪茄。
Sergeant, give me a couple of those good cigars.
噢!嘿!
Ow! Hey!
-你受伤了吗，维吉尔?  -这会让你感觉好些。
- Did it hurt you, Virgil? - This will make you feel better.
我们要好好谈谈，伙计们。你是从牛顿站来的吗?
We'll have a talk, fellas. Did you come through Newton Station?
-当然了。-那里有军队吗?
- Sure did. - Any troops there?
现在不是了。现在，阿拉巴马第六团，就在那里。
Not no more. Now, the Alabama Sixth, it was there.
但它随乔治亚第十团迁往维克斯堡。
But it moved to Vicksburg with the Georgia Tenth.
-第十届是维吉尔和我的旧部队。  - "曾经"是对的。
- The Tenth was Virg and my's old outfit. - "Was" is right.
我猜三四十英里内没有军队。
I guess there aren't any troops within 30 or 40 miles.
-至少60英里。 -你们这些卑鄙的叛徒!
- 60 at least. - (sheriff) You vile traitors!
你说维克斯堡?这就是我们要去的地方。
Vicksburg, you say? That's where we're headed for.
看来我们要打一场了。
Looks like we're in for a little fight.
-谢谢，伙计们。解开治安官。 -兴致勃勃，是吧，沃格?
- Thanks, fellas. Untie the sheriff. - High on the hog, huh, Virg?
嘿，看来你们这些美国佬和女人相处得不错啊。
Hey, looks like you Yankee boys do all right with the women.
(杰基·乔)你那只蓬松头发的挺漂亮的。
(Jackie Jo) And that's a pretty towheaded one you've got there.
-嗨。-你好，小姐。
- Hi. - Howdy, missy.
-嗨，小姐。-看到我跟你说的北边的事了吗?
- Hi, missy. - See what I told you about up North?
-中士，你的护手。 -很荣幸，先生。
- Sergeant, your gauntlets. - A pleasure, sir.
(维吉尔)嗨，小姐。嘿,小姐。
(Virgil) Hi, missy. Hey, missy.
把囚犯带走。
Remove the prisoner.
你要亲自开枪打他吗，队长?让杰基·乔来吧。
Are you going to shoot him personal, Cap? Let Jackie Jo here do it.
他是我见过最好的枪法。
He's the best dang shot I ever seen.
我曾经看见他射杀了一个逃跑的黑人女奴……
I once saw him shoot a runaway negro slave woman...
穿过…眼睛
right through the... eyes.
(用拳猛击)
(punch)
把他们绑起来。
Tie 'em up.
治安官，交给你了。手枪。装弹了。
Sheriff, I'll leave them in your hands. Pistol. It's loaded.
这是绿蔷薇的汉娜·亨特小姐的敬意。
With the compliments of Miss Hannah Hunter of Greenbriar.
-谢谢你，先生  -不客气，先生
- Thank you, sir. - You are welcome, sir.
满意了吗，亨特小姐?
Satisfied, Miss Hunter?
你的正义感确实让我有点惊讶。
Well, your sense of justice does surprise me a little.
正义吗?那些人都是多余的包袱。
Justice? Those men would have been excess baggage.
我不相信他们，但我真的相信……
I don't trust them any more than I really trust...
-比我强?  -没错。
- Than me? - That's right.
是的,女士。一个很难理解的人。
Yes, ma'am. A hard man to understand.
牛顿站在铁路交汇处
NEWTON STATION THE RAILROAD JUNCTION
为维克斯堡的联盟国部队提供物资
SUPPLYING THE CONFEDERATE FORCES AT VICKSBURG
-嗨，姑娘们! -北方佬!滚出去!
- Hi there, girls! - Yankees! Get out of here!
滚出去，你们这些肮脏的北方佬!滚出去!
Get out, you dirty Yankees! Get out of here!
-乔纳森! -亨特小姐。
- Jonathan! - Miss Hunter.
不能和囚犯说话。我们楼上为你准备了一间不错的房间。
Mustn't talk to the prisoners. We've got a nice room for you upstairs.
-给你洗个热水澡。-你可以换衣服。
- A nice hot bath for you. - You can change your clothes.
你看，我们有很多工作要做。
You see, we've got a lot of work to do.
-你不会把镇子烧了吧?  -没有。只是战争物资。
- You're not going to burn the town? - No. Just war supplies.
棉花。铁路设备。违禁品,女士。
Cotton. Railway equipment. Contraband, ma'am.
违禁品。那是我，对吧?
Contraband. That's me, ain't it?
来吧!下马!
Come on! Dismount!
-干得漂亮，理查德。 -谢谢，先生。
- Neatly done, Richard. - Thank you, sir.
-这就是全部驻军吗?  -每一个人。
- Is this the whole garrison? - Every last man.
他们不费吹灰之力就放弃了，就像凯撒对克利奥帕特拉那样。
They gave up without a struggle, like Caesar to Cleopatra.
毫不费力，是吧?
Without a struggle, huh?
柯比，把总部设在这家酒店。
Kirby, set up headquarters in this hotel.
-很乐意效劳，先生  -关上酒吧
- It would be a pleasure, sir. - And close the bar.
-是的，先生-我们开始今天的工作吧?
- Yes, sir. - Shall we set about the day's work?
我很想点燃这群叛逆者。
I'm going to love setting a torch to this nest of rebels.
囚犯!
Prisoner!
-叛军上校，长官  -什么事长官
- Rebel colonel, sir. - Yes, sir?
仓库里的违禁品是什么还有那些车里的?
What is the contraband in the warehouses and on those cars in the sidings?
美利坚联盟国的财产不是违禁品，长官。
The property of the Confederate States of America is not contraband, sir.
哦?
Oh?
让我们从我的角度来看，上校。
Well, let's look at it from my side, Colonel.
-乔纳森!乔尼英里。 -你认识上校?
- Jonathan! Jonny Miles. - You know the Colonel?
当然。我们是老朋友了。我们上次一起服役是打印第安人。
Sure. We're old friends. Last time we served together was fighting Indians.
手臂的事我很抱歉。什么时候发生的?
Sorry about the arm. When did that happen?
我既不需要你的关心，也不需要回忆我们的交往。
I want neither your solicitude nor to recall our association.
您允许我退下吗，长官?
Have I your permission to retire, sir?
把他带走。
Take him away.
我无法想象像迈尔斯这样的人会这么轻易放弃。
I can't figure a man like Miles giving up that easy.
他是西点军校的。像钉子一样坚韧。
He's West Point. Tough as nails.
也许失去那只手臂对他影响很大。
Maybe losing that arm took a lot out of him.
我认识的那个人即使失去双臂也会把你踢死。霍皮?
The man I knew could lose both arms and still try to kick you to death. Hoppy?
-你在这整片区域设立了纠察队吗? -是的，长官。
- Did you picket this whole area? - Yes, sir.
上校!有一辆叛军火车进站了，长官。
Colonel! There's a reb train coming in, sir.
西科德!伍德沃德!
Secord! Woodward!
这家酒吧关门了。
This bar's closed.
(火车驶来的汽笛声)
(whistle of approaching train)
那一定是一列补给火车正驶来。
Well, it must be a supply train - rolling right into our laps.
我从没见过没有警卫的补给火车。
I never saw a supply train without guards on it before.
他们在自己的地盘上不会太警觉。
They wouldn't be too alert in their own territory.
-那个叛军上校在哪里?  -电报局。
- Where was that reb colonel? - The telegraph office.
-电报局?  -是的，先生。
- Telegraph office? - Yes, sir.
好了，西科德，你知道该怎么做。
All right, Secord, you know what to do.
把那些马藏起来!
Get those horses under cover!
给他们马车!
Get them wagons!
把那包东西拿开。小心!
Get that bale off there. Watch it!
向下，看不见了。
Down, out of sight.
从里面掩护。
Cover from inside.
(火车汽笛)
(train whistle)
-长官?  -不，我不需要。
- Sir? - No, I don't need it.
-所有人都准备好了，长官-谢谢
- Everyone's ready for action, sir. - Thank you.
(枪声)
(gunfire)
开火!
Fire!
我不想这样。我尽量避免交战。
I didn't want this. I tried to avoid a fight.
这就是我从医的原因。
That's why I took up medicine.
-看那个白痴! -约翰尼·!乔尼英里!
- Look at that idiot! - Jonny! Jonny Miles!
停止射击!
Cease fire!
(喇叭)
( bugle)
-好吧，把他抬上去。-把他抬上去。
- (Kendall) All right, move him up. - Move this man up.
让我来帮忙。我是一名医生。马文医生。
Let me be of assistance. I'm a physician. Dr Marvin.
肯德尔少校。我们感谢你的帮助。
Major Kendall. We appreciate your help.
这个人是下一个。
This man is next.
去呼吸点新鲜空气。
Go get some air.
-我可以帮忙。-滚出去。
- I can help. - Get out.
把他弄出去。
Get him out of here.
卢，你去拿点冰来。所有你能找到的。
Lou, you go and get some ice. All you can find.
你也一样。你帮他。快。
You too. You help him. Quick.
(爆炸)
(explosions)
你要干多久，肯德尔?
How long are you going to be, Kendall?
自己看看吧。我们才刚刚开始。
Take a look for yourself. We just started.
-我需要一个明确的答复。 -我不能给你答复。
- I need a definite answer. - I can't give you one.
你知道，我也有工作要做。
I've got a job to do too, you know.
至少五个小时。
At least five hours.
上校。嘿,上校。
Colonel. Hey, Colonel.
你好,骑兵。
Hello, trooper.
我是鲍勃。巴德·巴德斯。
I'm Hoskins. Bud Hoskins.
K连，长官。
K Company, sir.
-你不认识我。 -我当然认识你。
- You don't know me. - Sure I know you.
好士兵。你就安心的躺着，孩子。
Good soldier. You just lie easy, son.
我把手放在上面，然后…
I put my hand on there and it's all...
躺着别动。
Just lie still.
你会给我妈写信吗，上校?她会喜欢的，如果你…
You'll write my ma, Colonel? She'd love it if you...
不久你就会亲自给她写信。
You'll be writing her yourself before long.
不。
No.
不，我知道。
No, I know.
-我很害怕，上校  -没什么好怕的。
- And I'm scared, Colonel. - There's nothing to be scared of.
不，我很好。
No, I'm all right.
抓住我，先生。
Just hold onto me, sir.
给我妈写信。
And write my ma.
我会永远欠你的。
I'll be in your debt forever.
你不感到骄傲吗?
Aren't you proud?
是的，我为那个男孩感到骄傲。
Yes, I'm very proud of that boy.
-报告。- 3死18伤
- Report. - Three dead, 18 wounded.
拆除正在按命令进行，先生，酒吧已经关门了。
Demolition proceeding as ordered, sir. And the bar is closed.
酒吧开门了!
The bar is open!
-拿点鸦片酊。 -没有了，先生。
- Get some laudanum. - There is no more, sir.
快下来，老兄，除非你想跟它一起上去。
Come down out of there, buster, unless you want to go up with it.
(爆炸)
(explosion)
约翰，这可是价值五十万美元的铁路设备。
Well, John, there goes half a million dollars of railroad equipment.
我就是这样谋生的，你知道的。建设铁路。
That's how I made my living, you know. Building railroads.
(爆炸)
(explosion)
8英里长的铁路都完了!北方和南方……
The railroad's finished for eight miles! North and south...
约翰，你在干什么?等一下!
John, what are you doing? Wait a minute!
-约翰! -滚出去!
- John! - Get out!
-你以为这是医院? -听我说。
- You figure this is a hospital? - Listen to me.
我也可以对上校这么做!滚出去。
And I can do it to colonels, too! Get out of here.
(爆炸)
(explosion)
(explosions)
当我们离开时，给你的人，伤员，酒。
When we move out, give your people - the wounded - a lot of liquor.
无论如何我都会这么做。
I'd do that anyway.
爆炸(继续)
(explosions continue)
来，拿着这个。
Here, take this.
它会让你稳定下来。
It will steady you down.
我以前从没见过这种情况。
I've never seen it this way before.
我父亲死的时候我在他身边。
I was with my father when he died.
但他平静地去世了。
But he died peacefully.
-没有痛苦。 -嗯，很幸运。
- Without pain. - Well, it was lucky.
-给你们俩。 -(男人尖叫)
- For both of you. - (man screaming)
说吧，肯德尔!玩得开心点!
Go ahead, Kendall! Have a field day!
什么意思，开心点?
What do you mean, field day?
他在为拯救人们的生命而战。
He's fighting to save men's lives.
男人的生活吗?还是他的职业声誉?
Men's lives? Or the reputation of his profession?
-你不是认真的吧，马洛上校  -随你便，女士
- You can't be serious, Colonel Marlowe. - Have it your way, ma'am.
-医学是最高尚的…   -当然，高尚的职业，高尚的誓言。
- Medicine is the most noble... - Sure, noble profession, noble oath.
灯笼高高举起。如此之高，以至于他们不愿承认自己正在摸索……
Lanterns held on high. So high they won't admit they're groping for...
-你太不公平了…  -不公平?
- You're unfair and... - Unfair?
里面有个女孩比那个男孩大不了多少。
There was a girl not much older than that boy in there.
我当时没有不公平，明白吗?
I wasn't unfair then, understand?
因为他们用了很多花哨的词，一个路段工都听不懂。
Because they used a lot of fancy words that a section hand wouldn't understand.
所以我按住她，其中两个人给她治疗。
So I held her down while two of 'em worked on her.
那时我相信医生。相信他们。
I trusted doctors then. Believed in 'em.
因为我爱她，我不想看到她死。
Because I was in love and I didn't want to see her die.
他们说是肿瘤。
A tumour, they said it was.
它必须马上取出来。
And it had to come out right away.
所以他们在她嘴里塞了条皮带这样当他们切到里面的时候
So they stuck a leather strap in her mouth so she could bite off her screams
她就能忍住自己的尖叫。
while they cut away to get in there.
他们发现了什么?没有什么!
And what did they find? Nothing!
哦，他们很遗憾。当然，他们犯了一个错误。
Oh, they were sorry. Sure, they'd made a mistake.
在下次实验之前，他们有事要谈。
They had something to talk about before their next experiment.
但是我呢?他们让我求她不要死。
But what about me? They left me begging her not to die.
我失去了妻子。
I lost my wife.
他们两个我都没杀。
I didn't kill either one of them.
我一定是疯了，或者太平常了。
I must have been crazy, or too conventional.
精彩的演讲。我想我有点醉了。
Quite a speech. I guess I'm feeling my liquor.
(喊着口令)
(shouted orders)
哇!
Whoo!
-谢谢你，医生。 -不客气，女士。
- Thank you, Doctor. - You're welcome, ma'am.
谢谢,汉克。
Thanks, Hank.
-我们差点就骗到你了。-差不多。
- Well, we almost fooled you. - Almost.
你不会成功的，汉克。他们已经把你包围了。
You'll never make it, Hank. They're already closing in on you.
贝德福德·福斯特紧跟在你后面。
Bedford Forest is sniffing at your heels.
你直奔安德森维尔的监狱而去。
You're headed straight for that prison at Andersonville.
在这方面我们无能为力。南方正在挨饿。
There's nothing we can do to help you there. The South is starving.
乔纳森，我只是在行医。
Jonathan, all I'm doing is practising medicine.
蠢人会做所有的考虑。
Old ironhead does all the thinking.
他认为事情很好。西点军校?
He thinks things pretty good. West Point?
不，是路段工。
No, section hand.
苏珊和孩子们好吗?  -他们很好。
- How are Susan and the kids? - They're fine.
在维克斯堡。我想你很快就能见到他们了。
In Vicksburg. I expect you'll be seeing them soon.
想得美，乔纳森。不错的尝试。
Nice try, Jonathan. Nice try.
维克斯堡见，霍比。
See you in Vicksburg, Hoppy.
-再见，霍比。 -再见，医生。
- Goodbye, Hoppy. - Goodbye, Doctor.
我想感谢你让我学到的一切。
I want to thank you for all I've learned.
我要尽可能多地活着回家。
I shall endeavour to get home alive as many as I can.
你是个好人，霍比。
You're a good man, Hoppy.
这件事结束后，如果我们不再见面，一定要读完医学院。
After this thing is all over, if we don't meet again, be sure and finish medical school.
我会强调这一点的，先生。
I shall make a point of it, sir.
再见,大夫。祝你好运。
Goodbye, Doctor. And good luck.
谢谢你，医生，谢谢你的帮助。
Thank you, Doctor, for all your help.
维克斯堡。他们往西南方向的巴吞鲁奇去了。
Vicksburg. They're headed southwest to Baton Rouge.
巴吞鲁奇。
Baton Rouge.
这里是巴吞鲁奇，少校。告诉福斯特将军。
It's Baton Rouge, Major. Tell General Forest.
(西科德)是的，你可以。我是调查委员会的成员。我知道该怎么做。
(Secord) Yes, you can. I'm on the board of inquiry. I know exactly what can be done.
现在，他没有权利，即使作为一个…
Now, he has no right, even as a...
-菲尔……  -什么事，约翰?
- Phil... - Yes, John?
牛顿站发生的事我很抱歉。
I'm sorry about what happened back at Newton Station.
算了吧，约翰。你太紧张了。
Forget it, John. You were under a strain.
但既然你提起了这个话题…
But since you brought up the subject...
你知道吗，约翰，我比你年纪大。
You know, John, I'm an older man than you are.
更重要的是，我是一个政治家。
What's more, I'm a politician.
我们已经攻破了牛顿站。
We've knocked over Newton Station.
这是我的…我们的记录。
It's a glorious thing on my... our records.
但现在是时候向北走了，回到拉格兰奇……
But now is the time to head north, back to La Grange...
我们承诺了，菲尔，就这样。
We're committed, Phil, and that's that.
固执。固执!
Stubborn. Stubborn!
哎哟。
Ouch.
医生，我能喝点那种酒吗?
Can I have some of that liquor to swallow, Doc?
你没有一个足够好的借口。这是怎么回事，邓克?
You haven't got a good enough excuse. How'd this happen, Dunker?
我在牛顿砍了一根电线杆。
I was chopping down one of them telegraph poles back there in Newton.
-斧头弹到了我的腿上。 -(笑声)
- The axe ricocheted right onto my leg. - (laughter)
-去抓斧头。-没什么。
- Go arrest the axe. - It ain't nothing.
没什么,嗯?几乎是血液中毒。你该庆幸我看到你一瘸一拐的。
Nothing, huh? Almost blood poisoning. You're lucky I saw you limping.
哦,医生…
Aw, Doc...
你在上面放什么?泥土吗?
What are you putting on there? Dirt?
树苔。普通的绿色霉菌。我想它有某种治愈剂。
Tree moss. Ordinary green mould. It has some sort of healing agent, I imagine.
-你能想象吗? -我无法想象结果，上校
- You imagine? - I don't imagine the results, Colonel.
这是一种古老的夏安族印第安疗法。
This is an old Cheyenne Indian cure.
啧啧!夏安印第安疗法!
Tsk! Cheyenne Indian cure!
绿色霉菌!树苔!
Green mould! Tree moss!
你戴着这个。有任何疼痛向我报告。
You keep this on. Report any soreness to me.
卢姬 !
Lukey!
-他们为什么要开枪，汉娜小姐?  -没事的。
- What for they shoot me, Miss Hannah? - It's all right.
(肯德尔)拿我的包。
(Kendall) Get my bag.
-她走了，夫人。-哦，不。
- She's gone, ma'am. - Oh, no.
(哭泣)
(sobs)
你没事吧，汉娜小姐?
Are you all right, Miss Hannah?
我给你带了一小段蜡烛。
I brought you a little bitty piece of candle.
明天早上我们会为您准备热水的。
We'll have some hot water for you in the morning.
看这里。我给你找了块镜子。
And lookee here. I found a piece of looking glass for you.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
我希望你能……在这里可以休息一下。
I hope you'll... be able to get some rest here.
夫人，你一定知道我们对卢姬的看法。
You must know how we feel, ma'am, about Lukey.
我们多么后悔……
How much we regret...
我很抱歉……
how sorry I am...
在某种程度上，我们是…
that in some way we were the cause of...
卢姬并没有要求那样做。
Lukey isn't asking for that.
我希望我能让你走。
I wish I could let you go.
如果我给你一匹马然后放你走，
If I gave you a horse and let you go,
你能保证24小时内不告诉任何人我们的计划吗?
would you promise not to tell anybody our plans for the next 24 hours?
太迟了。
It's too late.
一切都太迟了。
It's too late for all of that.
没有更多的承诺。
No more promises.
现在什么都没有了。
No more anything now.
我很抱歉。真的很抱歉。
I'm sorry. Truly sorry.
邓克。
Dunker.
唉,
Agh!
-昨天那条腿还好好的。-是的，但是今天早上肿了。
- That leg was all right yesterday. - Yes, but this morning it got swolled.
-我不得不把裤腿扯断了。-药膏呢?
- I had to tear my trouser leg. - Where's the poultice?
开始有点痒，长官，所以我就把她拉开了。
It started into itching, sir, so I just yanked her off.
这是伤口开始愈合的迹象，你个笨蛋。
It was a sign it was beginning to heal, you fool.
进来，不然你就有麻烦了。
Come in here, or you're in trouble.
布朗，帮帮忙。
Brown, lend a hand.
在那里。
Over there.
-咖啡吗?  -谢谢。
- Coffee? - Thanks.
报告。
Report.
那是盐泉镇，长官，里面一个士兵也没有。
That's Salt Springs, all right, sir. Nary a soldier inside, neither.
只有几个老妇人，几家盐厂和一所男孩子学校。
Just some old women, a couple of salt mills and a school for little boys.
-盐厂需要烧掉。 -为什么要暴露自己?我们很幸运。
- The salt mills will need burning. - Why show ourselves? We've been lucky.
你管那叫咖啡?
You call that coffee?
我们不能错过他们。盐和弹药一样珍贵。
We can't pass 'em up. Salt is as valuable as ammunition.
我们在这里扎营，明早再打他们。
We'll bivouac here and hit them in the morning.
好吧，你说了算。
All right, you're the boss.
(灌篮，喝醉了)嗨，嗨，我们走吧没有“不能”这个词…
(Dunker, drunk)  Hi-ho, down we go There ain't no such word as "can't"...
-怎么回事?  -医生在给唐克尔的腿做手术。
- What's going on? - The doctor's working on Dunker's leg.
(酒后唱歌)
(drunken singing)
我离开了我的爱我的爱我离开了…
I left my love My love I left...
再干一回。
Take another pull.
啊，那是很好的商店酒，医生。谁打了约翰?
Ah, that's good store liquor, Doc. Who hit John?
-我得把它脱下来，邓克。-你说什么?
- I've got to take it off, Dunker. - What did you say?
我得把你的腿截下来。
I've got to take your leg off.
你要做什么?
You've got to what?
毒药太厉害了。明早你就会死。
The poison's gone too far. You'll be dead by morning.
那之后我还能怎么样呢，医生?一条腿吗?那之后我还能怎么样呢?
What can come of me after that, Doc? One leg? What can come of me after that?
我会给你绑上吊索让你得到最贴心的医护。
I'll rig a sling and leave you with the closest civilian care.
平民在乎吗?
Civilian care?
然后就进监狱了?安德森威尔?
Then comes prison next, huh? Andersonville?
这就是我的下场吗，医生!
Is that what happens to me, Doc?!
-很有可能。 -是的。
- Quite possibly. - Yeah.
对一个男人来说，这真是个艰难的选择。
That's a hell of a tough choice for a fella to have to make.
-不是吗?好吧，告诉我。不是吗?  -必须把它弄下来。
- Ain't it? Well, tell me. Ain't it? - It's got to come off.
好吧。
All right.
你可以直接开火。
You just fire away.
但在你开始锯之前，给我点氯仿的东西。
But before you start sawing, you give me some of that chloroform stuff.
-你害了我，医生  -我把我的都给你
- You put me out, Doc. - I'll give you what I got.
现在咬这个。帮我一下。按住他。
Now bite this. Give me a hand here. Hold him down.
神……上帝!
God... God!
杰斐逊军校
JEFFERSON MILITARY ACADEMY
很明显是突袭牛顿车站的那个纵队。
It's obviously the column that raided Newton Station.
维克斯堡的报告可能性不大。
That Vicksburg report was just a faint.
我以为会有一个旅的骑兵来这里。
I thought a brigade of cavalry was due here.
-他们今天晚些时候才会到  -你的建议太极端了
- They won't get here till late today, sir. - What you suggest is most extreme.
-我最大的儿子才16岁。-该死，先生!
- My oldest boy here is only 16. - Damn it, sir!
对不起，上校。我是说，大人……
I beg your pardon, Colonel. I mean, Reverend...
听着，我手下有个14岁的男孩，还有个72岁的男人。这是一场战争，长官。
Look, I've got a boy in my battery that's 14, a man that's 72. This is a war, sir.
趁他们打盹，我可以用弹片和葡萄砸他们，、。
I could start lobbing shrapnel and grape at them critters, catch 'em napping.
只是炫耀一下武力，也许我们可以拖住他们直到骑兵到来。
Just a show of force, then perhaps we can hold them off until the cavalry gets here.
-巴克斯代尔少校学员。-长官?
- Cadet Major Barksdale. - Sir?
集合你的部队。整个后备队。
Assemble your battalion. The entire complement.
泰勒和菲彻得了腮腺炎。
Taylor and Fitcher have the mumps.
把他们从值勤名册上划掉。你听到中尉说的了。
Scratch them from the duty roster. Well, you heard the Lieutenant.
请通知部队我们将在黎明出发。
You'll be pleased to inform the corps we shall move at dawn.
谢谢你，长官!
Thank you, sir!
(公鸡打鸣)
(cock crows)
注意!
Attention!
巴克斯代尔少校，你可以把你的纵队往前移。愿上帝保佑你们。
Cadet Major Barksdale, you may move your column forward. And God bless you.
右肩，扛枪!
Right shoulder, arms!
右转,正前方!
Right, face!
学员们，前进!
Cadets, forward march!
大人，我的孩子约翰尼。他是我唯一的亲人。
Reverend, my boy Johnny. He's all I've got left.
先是他的爸爸，然后是他的叔叔，他的兄弟。现在是他?
First his pa, then his uncles, his brothers. Now him?
他是我唯一的亲人了，牧师。我不会让他走的。
He's all I have left, Reverend. I'm not going to let him go.
布福德学员鼓手，你被解职了。
Cadet drummer Buford, you are relieved of duty.
(男孩啸声)
(boy squealing)
我想给邓克留点。
I'd save a little of that for Dunker.
我刚失去了他。
I just lost him.
你失去邓克了，嗯?
You lost Dunker, eh?
你让我们失去了一个好男人。
Well, you lost us a good man.
血液中毒。截肢。我想是心脏休克。
Blood poisoning. Amputation. A shock to the heart, I guess.
-我就不用截肢了，如果他…  -如果，也许，也许。
- I wouldn't have had to amputate if he'd... - lf, maybe, perhaps.
-怎么了，药师?  -路段工，我受够你了!
- What's the matter, medicine man? - Section hand, I've had you!
脱掉上衣!
Strip your blouse!
我认为你是对的。来吧。
I think you're right. Come on.
勤务兵!马!把他们带上来!
Orderly! Horses! Bring 'em up!
约翰尼!
Johnny!
约翰尼·布福德!
Johnny Buford!
约翰尼!
Johnny!
-规则是什么，上校?  -你自己定吧。
- What are the rules, Colonel? - Just make up your own.
你说过没规则的，上校。
You said no rules, Colonel.
站起来，喊冤者。
On your feet, croaker.
开火，彼得!
Fire Peter!
开火，保罗!
Fire Paul!
炮火，长官，隐藏的炮位。
Artillery fire, sir. Hidden battery.
那些只不过是孩子。学生。
Those are nothing but children. Schoolboys.
-只是几个军校的孩子。 -但他们保持队形。
- Just some kids from the military school. - But they keep coming.
吹号集合。
Sound assembly.
(喇叭)
( bugle)
至少圣乔不是孩子。
At least that Holy Joe ain't no kid.
(喊着口令)
(shouted orders)
停止!前排，跪下!
Halt! Front rank, kneel!
-准备好了!  -亨特小姐…
- Ready! - Miss Hunter...
瞄准!开火!
Aim! Fire!
后排，停!
Rear rank, halt!
跪!
Kneel!
准备好!瞄准!开火!
Ready! Aim! Fire!
你想做什么?建立野战医院?
What do you want to do? Set up a field hospital?
是的，你现在要做什么?
Yes, what are you going to do now?
恕我直言，我要离开这里了。
With all due respect, I'm going to get the hell out of here.
吹号召回!
Sound recall!
我告诉过你照顾好这个女人!
I told you to take care of this woman!
(爆炸)
(explosion)
上校，我抓到一个俘虏。你想让我拿他怎么办?
Colonel, I got me a prisoner. What do you want me to do with him?
-打他屁股。 -在底部?
- Spank him. - On the bottom?
你觉得呢?
Where do you think?
-停止! -等等，上校。
- Halt! - Hold it, Colonel.
-报告。 -叛军。他们把整条路都封锁了。
- Report. - Rebs. They got the whole road blocked.
-有多少?  -全是正规军，长官
- How many? - A full regiment of regulars, sir.
他们有两门火炮，正在沿路挖掘。
They got two pieces of artillery and they're digging in along the road.
我们唯一要做的就是杀回盐泉，然后向东走。
The only thing to do is fight our way back to Salt Springs and head east.
-你没看到那灰尘吗?  -骑兵。跟了我们三个小时。
- Haven't you seen that dust? - Cavalry. Following us for three hours.
上校，迪康说他很了解这个地区。不是吗，迪康?
Colonel, the deacon says he knows this country real good. Don't you, Deacon?
在这一带传福音，唱赞美诗好几年了。
Preaching the gospel, singing the praises of the Lord hereabouts for years.
现在开始祈祷也许是个好主意。
It might be a good idea to start praying right now.
迪康把逃跑的奴隶从沼泽走私到北方。
The deacon smuggled runaway slaves north out of here through the swamp.
-与地下铁路。 -你能把我们偷渡到南方吗?
- With the underground railway. - Could you smuggle us out south?
等一下。等一下。
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
哎呀，沼泽里全是流沙，响尾蛇……
Why, that swamp is full of quicksand, rattlers...
伊甸园也有它的苦难。
The Garden of Eden had its sufferance too.
跟我来，上校兄弟，穿过沼泽一直到亚米特河。
Follow me, brother Colonel, through the swamps all the way to the river Amite.
主啊，请仁慈地引导。
Lead kindly, Lord.
好吧，给自己弄几匹新马。
All right, get yourself a couple of fresh horses.
右翼，掩护。
By the right flank, take cover.
来吧!
Come on!
(大喊)
(shouts)
(马洛)快点!来吧!
(Marlowe) Come on! Come on!
走出去。来吧，小伙子们。
Move out. Come on, boy.
来吧，小伙子们。
Come on, boy.
继续前进!继续前进!来吧!
Keep moving! Keep moving! Come on!
继续前进。保持清醒，孩子。
Keep moving. Stay awake there, kid.
继续前进。抬起你的脚。
Keep moving. Pick up your feet.
约翰，你估计到巴吞鲁奇还有多远?
John, how far do you figure to Baton Rouge?
40英里。
40 miles.
在里那面保持活力!
Keep alive in there!
-你想让我现在道歉还是以后?  -为什么?
- You want me to apologise now or later? - For what?
-继续前进!  -我从没想过你能做到。
- Keep moving! - I never thought you could do it.
你知道，约翰，我已经完全放弃了竞选国会议员的念头。
You know, John, I've given up all thought of running for Congress.
有了这些记录，我就能当上州长。
With this on my record, by George, I can be Governor.
-继续前进!  -密歇根州州长。
- Keep moving! - Governor of Michigan.
你可以给你自己任命工作。铁路专员……
And you can name your own job. Railroad commissioner...
在我们到达之前，别再做竞选承诺。加入你的队伍。
Don't start making campaign promises till we get there. Join your regiment.
上校，从医学角度来说，我的职责是通知你
Colonel, my duty, medically speaking, is to inform you
让这些人靠自己的双手和膝盖行军。
that these men may make it on their hands and knees.
我们已经连续开了20个小时了。我们需要休息一下。
We've been 20 hours without a stop. We need a rest.
我有眼睛，肯德尔。
I've got eyes, Kendall.
我也有责任告诉你，如果我们吵架了…
It's also my duty to inform you that if we run into a fight...
就这些了，医生。
That is all, Doctor.
谢谢你，长官。
Thank you, sir.
列,停止!
Column, halt!
-伍德沃德。-哟!
- Woodward. - Yo!
第一小队，侦察桥的另一边。
First squad, scout the other side of the bridge.
一队，前进，唷!
First squad, forward, yo!
(马蹄声在桥上)
(hooves clatter on bridge)
我不知道你有没有听说。
I don't know if you've heard.
你的人大约比我们晚一个小时，很快就来了。
Your people are about an hour behind us, coming fast.
我听说过。
I've heard.
我们要去巴吞鲁奇。我们就把你留在这里。
We're going on to Baton Rouge. We'll leave you here.
你的乡亲会照顾你的。
Your own kind can take care of you.
-我相信他们可以。-是的。
- I'm sure they can. - Yes.
我…
I...
我很抱歉给你带来麻烦，还有耻辱…
I'm sorry for the hardship and...
我们对…我对你造成的伤害
the humiliation that we've... that I've caused you.
(枪声)
(gunshots)
把她带出去!
Get her out of here!
回撤!
Recall!
(喇叭)
( bugle)
把她带进小屋!
Get her in that cabin!
走吧，汉娜小姐。
Come on, Miss Hannah.
看来他们给我们设了个陷阱。
Looks like they've got us in a trap.
不要停!
Knock on it!
掩护我们!
Give us some cover!
伍德沃德上尉，快走!
Captain Woodward, move!
(枪声持续)
(gunfire continues)
别烦我。
Leave me alone.
我很好。别烦我，好吗?
I'm all right. Let me alone, would you?
小心。
Easy.
马上叫西科德上校。不是那边，是另一扇门。
Get Colonel Secord right away. Not that way, the other door.
-报告。 -这里到处是叛军。至少两门大炮。
- Report. - It's alive with rebs. At least two cannons.
-他们跑得太快了。-步兵?
- They jumped us so quick. - Infantry?
-树林里到处都是   -加入你的队伍
- The wood's full of 'em. - Join your troop.
-把他的靴子剪下来，山姆。 -没人能把靴子剪下来。
- Cut his boot off, Sam. - Nobody's cutting that boot off.
把他的靴子割下来。
Cut his boot off.
狠狠地摇晃一下。
Take a good stiff jolt.
这靴子20块呢，骑兵。
Those are $20 boots, trooper.
-拿点水。-谁，我吗?
- Get some water. - Who, me?
带上A连和那个牧师，不管他是谁。
Take A-troop and that reverend, or whatever he is.
找个渡口过河。包抄他们，带个号兵。
Find a ford someway across that river. Flank 'em. Take a bugler with you.
先生，谢谢你给我这个机会。
Sir, thank you for the opportunity.
约翰，这是个陷阱。他们想让我们过桥。
John, it's a trap. They want us to cross that bridge.
就像漏斗一样。
It'd be like going through a funnel.
在这种情况下，光荣投降没什么不光彩的。
In a position like this, there's nothing disgraceful about honourable surrender.
回你的部队去。把他们藏起来。
Get back to your troop. Keep 'em under cover.
-你是说…你要继续吗?  -滚出去!
- You mean... you're going on? - Get out of here!
带着那颗子弹，你走不远的。
You're not going far with that bullet in you.
你在慢慢地把它切出来。
You're taking your own sweet time about cutting it out of there.
你不是这里唯一受伤的人，上校。把我的包拿来。
You're not the only wounded man here, Colonel. Get me my bag.
现在，这可能会有点疼。
Now, this is going to hurt a little.
继续吧，肯德尔。
Go on with it, Kendall.
-哦!  -保持腿伸展。
- Ooh! - Keep that leg stretched.
请查看。
Probe, please.
(马洛唧唧的声音)
(Marlowe yelps)
你玩得开心吗?
Are you having fun?
你是幸运的。
You're lucky.
你可能不相信，上校，但我为你争取了一些时间。
You may not believe it, Colonel, but I bought you some time.
-几个小时?  -也许更多。
- A couple of hours? - Maybe more.
谢谢。
Thanks.
-密歇根第一团就位，长官   -伊利诺斯第一团就位，我们是第一名。
- First Michigan in position, sir. - First Illinois in position. We were first.
我很好。
I'm all right.
马上开始。
Get cracking.
全能的上帝。他来了。
God Almighty. Here he comes.
上马。
Mount up.
你听到了，柯比。上马。
You heard me, Kirby. Mount up.
你听到上校说的了!上马!
You heard the Colonel! Mount up!
上校。
Colonel.
迪康找到了一个可以涉水的地方。士兵们现在应该已经就位了。
The deacon found a place to ford. The men ought to be in position by now.
谢谢。掩护我们的后方。看看我们还有多少时间。
Thanks. Cover our rear. See how much time we've got.
是的,长官。
Yes, sir.
-你的马呢?  -沼泽里，长官
- Where's your horse? - Back in the swamp, sir.
-嘴唇干?  -是的，长官，但我的军号不是。
- Lips dry? - Yes, sir. But my bugle ain't.
-展示颜色。 -你听到了。
- Uncase the colours. - You heard him.
-你知道你的命令吗?  -你不合适。让我来带队。
- You know your orders? - You're not fit. Let me lead this charge.
有了这样的成功，我就能入主白宫了。
With a success like this, I could land in the White House.
-我们可能都会降落在…  -(枪声)
- We'll probably all land in the... - (gunfire)
回你的团去!
Get back to your regiment!
号兵，吹号冲锋!
Bugler, sound charge!
(喇叭)
( bugle)
向前方!开火，保罗。
Forwards! Fire Paul.
连队!
Company!
你受伤了，长官。
You're hurt, sir.
吹……小号,吹。
Blow... Trumpet, blow.
他们不能放弃。
They can't give up.
也许是疯狂，也许是勇敢。别让我解释。没有人能做到。
Maybe it's crazy, maybe it's brave. Don't ask me to explain it. Nobody can.
来吧，我们有很多工作要做。
Come on, we're going to have a lot of work to do.
号手，吹号回撤。
Bugler, sound recall.
还有吗?
Got any more?
来吧，再给我们一点。
Come on, give us some more.
还要多久，中士?军士长。
How much longer, Sergeant? Sergeant Major.
-快准备好了，先生  -好了，孩子们快点!放进去!
- Pretty near ready, sir. - All right, boys! Hurry it up! Lay it in!
不要停!
Knock on it!
出来吧!快出来!
Come on out! Get out of there!
-那些人能被转移吗?  -他们都很关键。
- Can those men be moved? - They're all critical.
-我可以和他们说话吗?  -我宁愿你不要。
- May I speak to them? - I'd rather you didn't.
他们必须保持安静。我把我所有的鸦片酊都给他们了。
They've got to be quiet. I've given them all the laudanum I have.
对好人来说，这是个糟糕的结局。
It's a lousy finish for good men.
会有个医生和那支部队在一起。牵上你的马。
There'll be a medic with that reb column. Get your horse.
我不能指望那个。
I can't count on that.
你是说你要留下来?
You mean you're staying?
-药在哪里就在哪里。-即使在安德森维尔?
- Medicine's where you find it. - Even in Andersonville?
即使在安德森维尔。
Even in Andersonville.
如果你把它拍掉，我不会怪你。握手吗?
I wouldn't blame you if you slap it away. Shake hands?
-医生，格雷少校。-好的，来了。
- Doctor, Major Gray. - All right, coming.
当你的下一个医生拆下绷带时……
When your next doctor takes that bandage off...
我知道。树苔。
I know. Tree moss.
再见，喊冤者。
So longer, croaker.
保重，路段工。
Take care, section hand.
你累了。你帮了大忙了。谢谢你。
You're tired. You've helped a lot. Thanks for it.
在我让你经历了那么多之后，这种感激的方式真差劲。
A poor way of being grateful after what I've put you through.
-你最好现在就走。-是的，我想我最好走。
- You'd better be going. - Yes, I guess I'd better.
看，汉娜·亨特。
Look, Hannah Hunter.
感谢上帝，我不会再伤害你了。
Thank God I won't be the cause of hurting you any more.
因为碰巧我爱上了你。
Because it happens I'm in love with you.
(远处的号角)
( distant bugle)
你回来后把剩下的告诉她。
Tell her the rest when you get back.
-你自己的，长官 -快走
- One of your own, sir. - Get going.
上校，他们就在我后面。
Colonel, they're right on my tail.
(马洛)走吧。
(Marlowe) Let's go.
医生，我们团里的外科医生能为你效劳吗?
Doctor, could our regimental surgeon be of any service to you?
我会很感激的。
I'd be grateful.